{
  "reference_number": "186",
  "clauses": [
    {
      "question": "1. What process should the Government use to set a new emissions reduction target in legislation?",
      "question_index": 0,
      "answer": "The Government sets a 2050 target in legislation now",
      "answer_index": 0,
      "notes": "Methane is what sustains life and one of the key elements for mother earth even found on Mars You cant stop it,but reduce it Wood\n burning is 1/10 of burning coal both Methane and wood are short lived. As the pop grows so does emissions The biggest threat is\n\n the human race"
    },
    {
      "question": "2. If the Government sets a 2050 target now, which is the best target for New Zealand?",
      "question_index": 1,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Net Zero emissions is not possible with no life As the world is Organic from when mother nature intended it to be. The Paris\n agreement is a hoax Carbon tax credits This still allows companies to produce emissions"
    },
    {
      "question": "3. How should New Zealand meet its targets?",
      "question_index": 2,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "Not pay other people to reduce theirs. Pine trees only play a small part and when cut down have a reversed effect As indicated with\n logs and flooding from forestry Pine trees should never be planted in gully ways Erosion To be environmentally sustainable Is to plant\n a lot more Natives. We only have 23% we need over 40% Native bush"
    },
    {
      "question": "4. Should the Zero Carbon Bill allow the 2050 target to be revised if circumstances change?",
      "question_index": 3,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "The climate Changes. We already no that 40% of the pop couldn't care about climate change this is evident all over the world from\n\n Palm tree oil One lady suggested growing hemp or the good old fashioned hemp rope or building a house out of hemp"
    },
    {
      "question": "5. The Government proposes that three emissions budgets of five years each (i.e. covering the next 15 years) be in place at any given time. Do you agree with this proposal?",
      "question_index": 15,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "We are already 25 years behind. Like US were more advanced in solar power and internet in remote places UN said reduce Livestock\n numbers by 35% Even when National and Labour turn a blind eye to this And we have M Bovis from slacken Bio Security Which is from\n years of abuse on the environment Omen from conventional and intensive farming practices."
    },
    {
      "question": "6. Should the Government be able to alter the last emissions budget (i.e. furthest into the future)?",
      "question_index": 4,
      "answer": "No - emissions budgets should not be able to be changed",
      "answer_index": 9,
      "notes": "If on the right track We no right wing couldn't care about climate change, Because everything they have done is to promote it"
    },
    {
      "question": "7. Should the Government have the ability to review and adjust the second emissions budget within a specific range under exceptional circumstances? See p36 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 5,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I do not have any info even on pages on web But as climate change targets will shift and needs reviewing all the time There is more\n than one thing Sewage, water is indefinite or putting your house next to a river. There is a 10 metre limit for a fence with Livestock\n\n and towns should be 30 metres plus Even though water is one of the most things exploited"
    },
    {
      "question": "8. Do you agree with the considerations we propose that the Government and the Climate Change Commission take into account when advising on and setting budgets? See p44 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 6,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I have not read any propose as yet nor have I found any on the web. Budgets will be blown And Democracy is a dirt word When the\n\nRMA & EPA need a complete over haul along with local body"
    },
    {
      "question": "9. Should the Zero Carbon Bill require Governments to set out plans within a certain timeframe to achieve the emissions budgets?",
      "question_index": 7,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "If we look at all the things that run society today and people numbers Which creates climate change as population grows Other\n\nplanets might seem appealing"
    },
    {
      "question": "10. What are the most important issues for the Government to consider in setting plans to meet budgets? For example, who do we need to work with, what else needs to be considered?",
      "question_index": 8,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "NZ as a whole public"
    },
    {
      "question": "11. The Government has proposed that the Climate Change Commission advises on and monitors New Zealand's progress towards its goals. Do you agree with these functions? See p42 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 9,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "And we should have records Transition Water land and industries and Air. Water travels and under ground contaminates enter From\nfertilizers high based nitrogen and phosphorus and urban from products that go down the drain as grey water ends up in storm\n\ndrains"
    },
    {
      "question": "12. What role do you think the Climate Change Commission should have in relation to the New Zealand Emissions Trading Scheme (NZ ETS)?",
      "question_index": 10,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "not at mo Carbon incentives and tax credits and Paris agreement are the wrong way to go"
    },
    {
      "question": "13. The Government has proposed that Climate Change Commissioners need to have a range of essential and desirable expertise. Do you agree with the proposed expertise? See p45 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 11,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "not at mo the people of the planet need to have a say. expertise is not always the right way to go If it didnt"
    },
    {
      "question": "14. Do you think the Zero Carbon Bill should cover adapting to climate change?",
      "question_index": 12,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "If it didn't you would be in a sinking boat it is already sinking"
    },
    {
      "question": "15. The Government has proposed a number of new functions to help us adapt to climate change. Do you agree with the proposed functions? See p47 Our Climate Your Say",
      "question_index": 13,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "This should go further and way behind things should be put in place now. And I would say Councils and the EPA have got a lot to\n\nanswer for for what they think is the norm this might have been 20 years a go They are every destructive in their behavior land, sea\nYou have to think out side the box of anything to do with exploitation otherwise this has devastating effects for the next 100 years\n\nplus"
    },
    {
      "question": "16. Should we explore setting up a targeted adaptation reporting power that could see some organisations share information on their exposure to climate change risks?",
      "question_index": 14,
      "answer": "Yes",
      "answer_index": 3,
      "notes": "7 million die each year for air pollution China s the worst culprit more people of cause Lets burn coal only for the production of steel\n\njust as long it is not made in China Where we have more drugs coming into the country Free trade greater Bio Security risks"
    },
    {
      "question": "Do you have any other comments you'd like to make?",
      "question_index": 16,
      "answer": null,
      "answer_index": 5,
      "notes": "I have seen the effects of climate change and have been in rural environments for 35 years , from erosion polluted water ways\n\ndamaged soil slips years ago when I was young raw sewage going into Wellington harbor from Petone A truck full of S4 ended up in\nWellington Harbor How many people can you fit on a 1 k Island or in a Mini old school Or how to turn a rain Forrest in to a desert If you\nplant a tree in the same spot for years in a desert eventually you will end up with a Forrest Agri research was putting Super on low hills\n\nto increase clover growth every slow and destructive behavior Understand the laws of nature and the way the environment works\nWhat you do is let the plants grow and go to seed works ever time"
    }
  ]
}
